<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vladimir Rozhkov</title>
    <link>https://www.rozhkov.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vladimir Rozhkov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 | Follow on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/xrozhokx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.rozhkov.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>О найме в компанию и на проекты</title>
      <link>https://www.rozhkov.me/blog/company-vs-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 10:02:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rozhkov.me/blog/company-vs-project/</guid>
      <description>Наниматься в компанию или проект? &amp;ldquo;Работать в нашем банке — большая честь&amp;rdquo; © Думаю, все помнят притчу о мотивации — где три каменотеса на вопрос, чем они заняты, отвечали, последовательно, &amp;ldquo;я обтесываю камень и несчастен потому что мало платят&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;я обтесываю камень и рад что у меня есть работа и я могу кормить семью&amp;rdquo; и &amp;ldquo;я строю храм!&amp;rdquo;. Задачей и мотивацией каждого инженера должно быть именно строительство храмов. Не работа ради денег, не работа ради работы, а работа ради осязаемого результата.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://www.rozhkov.me/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rozhkov.me/cv/</guid>
      <description>Java, Python, Node.JS, Bash, Spring (Boot/Cloud), Netflix OSS, Spark, AWS, DevOps, (No)SQL, REST, Microservices, Docker, BDD/TDD, Gradle/Maven, Git, Jenkins, Jira, IntelliJ IDEA, etc…
Experience Software Development Engineer at OneDome, Kyiv, Ukraine June 2015 – present
Doing awesome stuff with awesome people
Technical Manager at NetCracker, Kyiv, Ukraine January 2013 – May 2015
CRM REST APIs project:
 Project goal: development of REST API’s for existing NC components Acted as Project Manager, Technical Manager, SME I&amp;rsquo;ve designed REST API’s for three business-critical NetCracker components Proved that REST should be mainstream approach for building API’s Created API guidelines and best practices for new components Managed team from 4 devs, few QA’s and two performance engineers as lead architect and project manager Delivered project in-time and in-budget Technologies: Java, JAX-RS, Spring, rest-assured  Order Entry project:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the beginning was the Word,..</title>
      <link>https://www.rozhkov.me/blog/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 23:30:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rozhkov.me/blog/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>And the Word was with God, and the Word was God.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>